Eddie Germano Cartoons
Eddie Germano Cartoons
1964-1987
1964-1968
Germano, Eddie.
1.75 linear ft.
Original editorial cartoons from 1964-1987
2649256
Biographical History
Eddie Germano (1924- ) is an American editorial and sports cartoonist.
Eddie Germano was born in Boston on November 15, 1924. At age 16, he started working in the office at the Boston Post. After serving in the Army and landing his first full-time cartooning job in 1948, Germano worked at several Florida and Massachusetts newspapers. In 1963 he joined the staff of the Brockton Enterprise where he created sports and editorial cartoons. At age 66, Germano left the Enterprise to pursue freelance work.
In addition to his newspaper cartoons, Germano worked on other various cartoon projects. Germano produced a cartoon television show for three years and beginning in 1971, Germano contributed special sports features to the Boston Globe. Around this time he also drew a daily sports feature for Columbia in New York. During the 1990s, Germano worked with Tom McCormick on Mr. Speaker, a strip that was never published.
Germano is particularly well known for his cartoons featuring Boston's sports teams. In 1989 his book Red Sox Drawing Board was published and Germano won an award for his cartoon series about heavyweight boxer Rocky Marciano who was raised in Brockton. Some of his cartoons have also been exhibited at the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, New York.
Germano is a member of the National Cartoonists Society which recognized Germano with its 1981 and 1992 sports cartoon awards.
Eddie Germano continues to draw privately commissioned cartoons.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Eddie Germano Cartoons contain original editorial cartoons published in the Brockton (Mass.) Enterprise. The bulk appeared between 1964 and 1968, but there are also three that were published during the 1980s. The cartoons are drawn with ink and graphite on illustration board. Four are accompanied by Germano's explanatory comments.
Arrangement of the Collection
The bulk of the cartoons are arranged in chronological order. Four cartoons acquired in a later donation are placed at the end.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Germano, Eddie.; The Enterprise (Brockton, Mass); Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Editorial cartoons -- Massachusetts.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Political cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Massachusetts -- Politics and government -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Editorial cartoons.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Majority gift of Eddie Germano, 1968.
Four items gift of Susan L. Biel, 2017.
Inventory
- Cartoons, Brockton (Mass.) Enterprise, See below for an index to the cartoons.
  Gift of Eddie Germano, 1968.
  - Cartoons, 1964 Jul; 1 item (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1965 Jan-Feb; 2 items (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Jan-Mar; 10 items (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Apr-Jul; 10 items (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Aug, Oct-Dec; 12 items (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Jan, Mar-Apr; 10 items (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1967 May; 9 items (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Jun-Aug; 12 items (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Sep-Oct; 15 items (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Nov-Dec; 8 items (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Jun; 1 item (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, undated; 11 items (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
- Cartoons, Brockton (Mass.) Enterprise
  Gift of Susan L. Biel, 2017.
  - Cartoons, 1964; 1983,; 1986-1987; accompanied by the cartoonist's typeset descriptions; 4 items (Folder 1)
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may appear under an alternative term.
B= Box, MC=Map Case, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1, MC1 = Map Case, Folder 1.
Asia B2F1
automobile accidents B1F1 B2F2
Britain B2F2
budget B1F3 B2F1
Canada B2F3-B2F4
cancer B1F4
capital punishment B2F1 B2F4
China B1F5 B2F6
Congress B2F4 B2F6
crime B1F1
de Gaulle, Charles B1F4 B2F4
debt B2F1
Democratic Party B1F4-B1F5 B2F5
demonstrations B2F2-B2F3
drug use B2F1 B2F4
Dukakis, MichaelMC1
elections B2F4
Erhard, Ludwig B2F7
Expo 67 B2F3
fashion B1F1
France B1F4 B2F1 B2F4
Gandhi, Indira B1F4
Garrison, Jim B2F1
Germany B1F5 B2F6
Hicks, Louise Day B2F5
Ho Chi Minh B1F5
holidays B1F4 B2F5
Iran-Contra affairMC1
Israel B2F3
Japan B2F1
Johnson, Lyndon Baines B1F3 B1F5 B2F2-B2F3 B2F6
Kennedy, Ted B1F5
King, Ed (governor of Massachusetts)MC1
Massachusetts B1F3-B1F5 B2F1-B2F6
Mayor Sims B1F5
McNamara, Robert B2F6
Meany, George B1F3
Middle East B2F3
Nasser, Gamal Abdel B2F3
National Newspaper Week B1F5
New England B1F1
Nixon, Richard M. B2F6
nuclear weapons B2F4 B2F6
oil B2F4
peace B2F2
Poland B2F4
politics B1F3
prices B1F5 B2F6
Republican Party B2F2 B2F5
Reuther, Walter B2F4
Romania B1F4
Russia B1F4
schools B1F5 B2F3
Soviet Union B1F4
space exploration B1F4-B1F5 B2F5
spending B1F3
sports B2F3
Stalin, Svetlana B2F1
stock market B1F4
taxes B1F2-B1F3 B2F1 B2F3-B2F4 B2F6 MC1
teachers B2F3-B2F4
Temple, Shirley B2F4
Titicut Follies B2F4
United Auto Workers B2F4 B2F6
unions B1F3
United Nations B1F2
Veteran's Day B1F5
Vietnam War B1F5 B2F2 B2F5
Volpe, John B1F5 B2F4-B2F5 B2F7
Wallace, George B1F3
war B1F4
War on Poverty B1F4 B2F5
weather B1F3 B2F1 B2F4-B2F5 MC1
welfare B2F4-B2F5
Wilson, Harold B2F5